JOOYOUN PAEK

SUMMARY

I design systematic UX models for products inclusive of digital and physical experiences. My strength is in understanding complex requirements, release cycles and organizational structure at global scale to produce simple solutions in sketch, motion prototypes, visual mock-ups and spec level design as needed. I've been solving realistic product problems for service onboarding, marketplace, voice Al, payment transactions, and multidevice experiences with design. I enjoy all kinds of research to identify human behavior patterns.

SKILLS

Design software

 Sketch, Principle, Origami, Adobe CS, SketchUp

Design research

 online survey, usage data analysis, competitive landscape analysis, academic in-depth research,
 AB testing, focus group interview, archeological visual research

Theatrical ptotype

 paper prototype, digital installation, Arduino circuit making

Basic programing

Processing, Max, HTML, CSS
 Project managment
 Storytelling with digital media

EXPERIENCE

2018-2019

Lead Designer, Viv Labs, San Jose

Designed Bixby Multi-Device & Marketplace UX for speaker, smartphone, tablet, watch and refrigerator for global market in collaboration with multi-cultural and lingual teams. Led visual studies on branding and listening animation of Voice Al. Partook in stakeholder presentations, design team operation and project manager role.

2012-2018

Senior Designer, Samsung Electronics. Seoul

Designed Service UX for Android Smartphone, Tablet and Tizen Watch from concept to shipment.

- Bixby basic Interaction, settings, onboarding design and dialog writing
- Samsung Pay payment flow and gift card store design
- Physical training app for mobile and watch
- Samsung Account onboarding and setting redesign
- Samsung content store
 & user library redesign

2007-2012

Associate Creative Director, R/GA, New York

Led Nike+ Running creative team for Nike+ Maps that became the platform for Nike Running events and GPS Watch. The work included ideation, consumer experience definition, directing visual design, and part managing workstreams with the geospatial service vendor, Johnson McLean. Designed voice feedback feature for the Nike+ GPS App. Created the consumer experience flow and wireframes for a 360° marketing campaign and e-commerce site for Barnes & Noble e-reader, nook.

jypaek@gmail.com | 650-250-9966 jooyounpaek.com | Palo Alto, CA

Created user journeys and designed the desktop, mobile and retail experience for the '3-Year-Future' of Nokia.com global e-commerce site.

2011

Adjunct Professor, Interactive Telecommunications Program, Tisch School of Art, New York University

Taught experience design for graduate students.

2002-2003

Designer, Jin Sculpture Research & Doga Architecture Studio, Seoul

Designed miniature figures and relief sculpture for a \$7 million commission from the Korean Ministry of Defense.

EDUCATION

2018-2019

Stanford University Professional Studies Classes

The Architecture of Information by Barry Katz Art of conversation by Lisa Quiano

2005-2007

Master of Professional Studies, Interactive Telecommunications Program, New York University

Recipient, Tisch School of the Arts Fellowship for two years.

1996-2000

Master of Fine Arts & Design, Seoul National University

1996-2000

Bacheler of Art & Education, Seoul National University

Recipient, Outstanding Student Scholarship for all years Instructor of undergraduate ski introduction class Internship, middle school art class Art tutor for highschool, elementry and pre-school students

AWARDS

2017-2019

Bixby Conversation UX Design

Al Tech Award

The Good Design Awards

2018

Samsung Pay UX Design

Best New Innovation, Mobile World Congress

2011

Nike+ GPS Running UX Design

Facebook 8 Zuckerburg Livestream Grand Prize, User Experience Awards The Webby The Clio The One Show

PATENT

2016

Electronic device including electronic payment system and operating method thereof

United States Patent Application 20150032544

PUBLICATIONS

2009

Too Smart City Sentient City, MIT Press

Design principles and making process of Too Smart City, commissioned by The Architecture League of New York.

2005-2008

JooYoun Paek as creator

Making Things Talk by Tom Igoe Rhizome Interview by Tyler Coburn Domus Magazine article 4dsocial Magazine by Despina Papadopoulos Craft Magazine by Laura Kiniry Theme Magazine by Jerome Chou Alarm Magazine by Rihoko Ueno

SHOWS & WORKSHOPS

2019

The Pillowig

24/7, Somerset House, London

2009-2008

Fold Loud

SIGGRAPH, LA

Design and Elastic Mind, MoMA, NY

2008

The Polite Umbrella

SEAMLESS, MIT & Museum of Science, Boston

2009-2008

Not Bicycle Cover

The Future Is Not What It Used To Be, Postmasters Gallery, New York & Warsaw Museum of Art, Poland

2008

The Polite Umbrella

SEAMLESS, MIT

& Museum of Science, Boston

2011

Expand-A-Bag Workshop, EYEBEAM

Created useful objects from commercial plastic bags with local creators.

ORGANIZATIONS

2009-2010

Resident Artist.

Lower Manhattan Cultural Council

Designed guideline for how to butcher the famous
Wall Street Bull statue.

2008-2009

Resident Artist, EYEBEAM Art and Technology Center

Created Not Bicycle Cover,

Rescue Dumpter and Too Smart City.

2004

Resident Artist,

Vermont Studio Center

Created the first version of Pillowig.